<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Path of Heavy Metal</name>
		<description>The Path of Heavy Metal from Valda’s Spire of Secrets</description>
		<author url="https://shop.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="barbarian-heavy-metal.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Path of Heavy Metal" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL">
		<supports> Heavy Metal Path</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The barbarians of the Path of Heavy Metal do not do things by halves. They fight the strongest foes, swing the biggest axes, and play the loudest music. For this reason, any battle they get involved in tends to be noisy, violent, and short.</p>
			<p class="indent">Armored only in face paint and studded belts, these fearless hellions are known for screaming their enemies into submission and trashing taverns, though they can also be thoughtful and erudite when not tapping into their primal fury. Away from the battlefield, the "thunderheads" form a tight fraternity, bonded together by absolute commitment to their path and the shared recognition that he life of an adventurer -with its grueling travel, explosive violence, and unfamiliar lodgings- is essentially a neverending tour.</p>
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_HEAVY_METAL_AXE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_SOLO_SHREDDING" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_KILLER_VOCALS" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_UP_TO_ELEVEN" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_SMASH_IT" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_HEAVY_METAL_AXE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_SOLO_SHREDDING" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_KILLER_VOCALS" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_UP_TO_ELEVEN" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_SMASH_IT" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Path of Heavy Metal feature</em></p>
			<p>When you choose this path at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with three musical instruments of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain proficiency with three musical instruments of your choice.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
    <element name="Heavy Metal Axe" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_HEAVY_METAL_AXE">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Path of Heavy Metal feature</em></p>
			<p>At 3rd level, your dabbling with craftsmen and bards has taught you how to build the sickest instruments possible. You can spend 8 hours of work converting a two-handed weapon into an instrument with which you are proficient. Only you can play an instrument weapon you have created, which retains all its combat capabilities. You can maintain a total number of instrument weapons equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can spend 8 hours of work converting a two-handed weapon into an instrument with which you are proficient. Only you can play an instrument weapon you have created, which retains all its combat capabilities. You can maintain a total number of instrument weapons equal to your proficiency bonus.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Solo Shredding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_SOLO_SHREDDING">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Path of Heavy Metal feature</em></p>
			<p>Also at 3rd level, you play your instrument weapon even in combat, rocking out as you crack skulls. When you enter a rage, you begin ferociously playing a solo on your instrument weapon. After you deal damage to a hostile creature during your rage with your instrument weapon, you increase your Rage bonus damage by 1. You can increase your Rage damage bonus up to a maximum of twice your proficiency bonus. This increase lasts until you are incapacitated, you are no longer holding your instrument weapon, you miss an attack, or your rage ends.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you deal damage to an enemy with your instrument weapon while raging, you increase your Rage bonus damage by 1, to a maximum of +{{rage:damage:bonus}}, until you are incapacitated, no longer holding your instrument weapon, miss an attack or your rage end.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rage:damage:bonus" value="proficiency" bonus="double">
        </rules>    
	</element>
    <element name="Killer Vocals" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_KILLER_VOCALS">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Path of Heavy Metal feature</em></p>
			<p>By 6th level, as a bonus action, you can release a thunderous battle cry, blood-curdling screech, or growl. Each Large or smaller creature you choose within 5 feet of you is pushed 5 feet away from you and is deafened until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description> You can release a battle cry, screech, or growl. Each Large or smaller creature you choose within 5 feet of you is pushed 5 feet away from you and is deafened until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Up to Eleven" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_UP_TO_ELEVEN">
		<description>
			<p><em>10th-level Path of Heavy Metal feature</em></p>
			<p>Starting at 10th level, you put total commitment into your music. Whenever you make a Charisma check or any check that involves playing your instrument weapon, you can treat a d20 roll of 10 or lower as an 11.</p>
		<sheet>
			<description> Whenever you make a Charisma check or any check that involves playing your instrument weapon, you can treat a d20 roll of 10 or lower as an 11.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Smash It" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_HEAVY_METAL_SMASH_IT">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level Path of Heavy Metal feature</em></p>
			<p>By 14th level, you’ve learned that the best way to end a fight (and a performance) is to smash one of your instrument weapons entirely. When you hit a creature with your instrument weapon while you are raging, you can smash the weapon on the target, dealing an additional 4d12 damage. A nonmagical instrument weapon is completely destroyed, whereas a magical instrument weapon loses its musical components and becomes a normal weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
            <description>When you hit an enemy with your instrument weapon while raging, you can deal an additional 4d12 damage. A nonmagical instrument weapon gets destroyed, while a magical one loses its musical components and becomes a normal weapon.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
</elements>
