<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>College of Graffitti</name>
    <description>The College of Graffitti from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
    <author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
    <update version="0.0.1">
      <file name="bard-graffitti.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/bard-graffitti.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="College of Graffitti" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_GRAFFITTI">
    <supports>Bard College</supports>
    <description>
      <p>To many, the College of Graffiti is a nuisance, a band of hooligans that vandalize the city with no regard for the law. But bards who learn to tag know that graffiti is the single greatest art form. Graffiti artists use the entire city as their canvases, placing murals of inspiration where everyone can see them and personal tags where few will notice. Theirs is a bold, creative endeavor that, while illegal, breathes vibrancy into the city and emboldens those within it.</p>
      <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
      <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_STREET_ART" />
      <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_SIGNATURE_MARK" />
      <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_KALEIDOSCOPIC_SPRAY" />
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_STREET_ART" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_SIGNATURE_MARK" level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_KALEIDOSCOPIC_SPRAY" level="14" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
    <description>
      <p>Starting when you choose this college at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with painter's supplies and in your choice of the Stealth or Sleight of Hand skill.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description> You gain proficiency with painter's supplies and in your choice of the Stealth or Sleight of Hand skill.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
    	<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_PAINTERS_SUPPLIES" level="3" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Graffitti)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
		</rules>
  	</element>
  <element name="Street Art" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_STREET_ART">
    <description>
      <p>Also at 3rd level, you learn the tag cantrip, which counts as a bard cantrip for you, but doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known. When you cast the tag cantrip, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to spray out a mural. For the next minute, you and all friendly creatures within 30 feet of the mural that can see it gain a +1 bonus to ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws, up to a maximum of +3. You can use this ability again and expend more uses of Bardic Inspiration to expand this mural further, increasing the bonus by 1 each time.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description> You learn the tag cantrip. You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to spray out a mural. For the next minute, you and all friendly creatures within 30 feet of the mural that can see it gain a +1 bonus to ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws, up to a maximum of +3. You can use this ability again and expend more uses of Bardic Inspiration to expand this mural further, increasing the bonus by 1 each time.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TAG" level="3" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Signature Mark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_SIGNATURE_MARK">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 6th level, you can paint a target on a creature’s back. As a bonus action, you can attempt to magically spray a signature mark directly onto a creature you can see within 5 feet of you. Make a melee spell attack roll against that creature. On a hit, the creature is marked. Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature you have marked with a melee weapon attack, you can add 1d8 to the roll. Additionally, when a friendly creature makes an attack against a creature you have marked, you can use your reaction to grant advantage on the attack roll.</p>
      <p class="indent">A creature can remove its armor or outermost clothing or wash itself with soap as an action to remove its tag.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action">
      <description> Make a melee spell attack roll against a creature you can see within 5 feet of you. On a hit, the creature is marked. Once on each of your turns, when you hit a marked creature with a melee weapon attack, you can add 1d8 to the roll. Additionally, when a friendly creature makes an attack against a marked creature, you can use your reaction to grant advantage on the attack roll. The marked creature can removed the mark by spending an action either removing its armore or outermost clothing, or wash itself with soap.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Kaleidoscopic Spray" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GRAFFITTI_KALEIDOSCOPIC_SPRAY">
    <description>
      <p>Beginning at 14th level, as an action, you can let loose a flurry of magical paint, coating every surface. Each creature you choose in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or be blinded until the end of its next turn. Each creature in the area is marked by you, whether or not succeeds its saving throw.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
      <description> You let loose a flurry of magical paint. Each creature you choose in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or be blinded until the end of its next turn. Each creature in the area is marked by you, whether or not succeeds its saving throw.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>