<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Lion Banner</name>
		<description>The Lion Banner from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
		<author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="captain-lion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/captain-lion.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Lion Banner" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER">
        <supports>Banner</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bravery in the face of overwhelming odds, mastery of horsemanship, and unwavering honor are the hallmarks of captains of the Lion. This banner represents the very ideal of gallantry and fortitude that knights and paladins aspire to achieve. The mere sight of it inspires heroism in its troops, and a captain who flies it can turn even the most poorly equipped militia into a fit fighting force.</p>
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_MANEUVER_LIONS_CHALLENGE" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_SADDLE_SURE" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_REPOSITION" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_LIONS_GAMBIT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_MANEUVER_LIONS_CHALLENGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_SADDLE_SURE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_REPOSITION" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_LIONS_GAMBIT" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Maneuver: Lion's Challenge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_MANEUVER_LIONS_CHALLENGE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting when you choose this banner at 3rd level, you learn the following maneuver:</p>
            <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one battle die as a bonus action to challenge the target to a duel. Until the end of your next turn, that target has disadvantage on any attack roll that isn't against you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one battle die to challenge the target to a duel. Until the end of your next turn, that target has disadvantage on any attack roll that isn't against you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Saddle Sure" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_SADDLE_SURE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, you have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount, and if you fall off your mount, you always land on your feet unless you're incapacitated. In addition, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed.</p>
	     <p class="indent">Finally, you can force an attack targeted at your mount to target you instead.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount, and if you fall off your mount, you always land on your feet unless you're incapacitated. In addition, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed. Finally, you can force an attack targeted at your mount to target you instead.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Reposition" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_REPOSITION">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 13th level, you and up to three friendly creatures of your choice that you can see can each move up to 20 feet when you roll initiative. A creature can't benefit from this feature if its speed is 0.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> You and up to three friendly creatures of your choice that you can see can each move up to 20 feet when you roll initiative. A creature can't benefit from this feature if its speed is 0.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Lion's Gambit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_LION_BANNER_LIONS_GAMBIT">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, when you take damage from acreature that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature, and if you hit, you can add half your level to the damage roll.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can make this attack three times, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="3/Short||Long Rest">
            <description>When you take damage from a creature that is within 5 feet of you, you can make a melee weapon attack against that creature, and if you hit, you can add half your level to the damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>    
