<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
      <name>Warmage</name>
      <description>The Warmage from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
      <author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
      <update version="0.0.6">
        <file name="class-warmage.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/class-warmage.xml" />
      </update>    
    </info>
    <element name="Warmage" type="Class" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_WARMAGE">
		<description>
			<p>An elf recites the motions again for the simplest spell she knows, repeating them until she knows they are perfect. With a single, precise stroke, she unleashes a wave of arcane energy, focused into a searing blue beam.</p>
			<p class="indent">A tiefling waves her hands to conjure floating greatswords of humming blue energy, which dance about in mesmerizing and deadly arcs. One blade takes on an aspect of fire, and the other lightning, as she begins to cleave through the goblinoid horde. Waving a black and red checkered banner, a dragonborn king charges into the fore. At his sides are warmages of all houses, a chessboard of elite arcanists, poised to turn the tide of battle.</p>
			<p class="indent">The undisputed masters of cantrips, warmages turn the most fundamental types of magic into a deadly and precise art.</p>
			<h4>CANTRIP MASTERS</h4>
			<p>While other spellcasters aspire to grander and more complex spells, warmages refine and master the most fundamental magic: cantrips. Warmages wield their magic in the same way that a warrior uses a sword, bow, or axe: as weapons to be perfected and mastered, not as an unknowable force to be feared. In contrast to sorcerers and WARMAGEs, their magic is a trainable skill, one that can be mastered by almost anyone with discipline and aptitude. Therefore, warmages stand among the most fearsome of spellcasters, with only the most rudimentary of spells.</p>
			<h4>STRATEGIC GENIUSES</h4>
			<p>Warmages have a long and storied history as grand strategists and tacticians, both in grand battles and personal skirmishes. If a warmage is outgunned or outmanned, they'll try to outthink their foes, which works more often than not. They demonstrate an efficient kind of pragmatism, owing perhaps to their ability to solve many problems with a few magical tools.</p>
            		<h4>ALIGNED FREE AGENTS</h4>
			<p>While some warmages are fully self-taught, the majority join a House, a loose confederation of warmages which practice together and share secrets of the trade. Houses teach invaluable battlefield strategy, but each individual Houses also touts their own brands of tactics and styles of magical tricks. The House of Knights, for example, emphasizes armor and martial prowess, whereas the House of Kings emphasizes battlefield strategy.</p>
			<p class="indent">By way of metaphor, Houses which value honor and teamwork above all else brand themselves after games of strategy, whereas those who epitomize selfreliance name themselves for games of chance. This division in the warmage Houses is representative of a schism that dates back to the earliest warmage masters. Legend has it that the first two masters separated when one decided to found a college. The other, out of spite, built a casino outside its grounds.</p>
            		<h4>CREATING A WARMAGE </h4>
			<p>Warmages come from all walks of life, so as you build yours, consider where you first learned the fundamentals of magic, which you would go on to perfect. You might have picked up cantrips from a fellow adventurer or in the early stages of WARMAGEing training. You could even be self-taught. Choose an Arcane Initiation which best fits your character's history with magic.</p>
			<p class="indent">Moreover, consider how you feel about magic as a whole. Are you envious of other spellcasters, or are you confident you could best them regardless? Did you once pine to be a WARMAGE, but found you could never muster enough true magic to form a spell slot? Did you choose warmagistry to hone your talents to their absolute peak, or did you choose it to wield power no warrior can equal?</p>
			<p class="indent">Lastly, consider your prospective warmage house. Though you don't choose one until reaching third level, your aspirations might shape which house you favor the most. If you would like to dabble with greater arcane magic, the House of Bishops is the best fit. If the clashing of swords at the frontlines piques your interest, consider the House of Knights.</p>
            		<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a Warmage quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Make Strength your third highest if you plan to take the House of Knights. Then choose the cantrips <i>chill touch</i>, <i>force weapon</i>, and <i>phantom grapnel</i>, and the Adventurer Arcane Initiation. Pick any background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a warmage, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per warmage level</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per warmage level after 1st</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
				<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
				<li><strong>Tools:</strong> One Artisan's kit, one musical instrument</li>
			</ul>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
				<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Arcana, Athletics, History, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, and Survival</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Leather armor, a dagger, and any simple weapon</li>
				<li>A spellcasting focus or material component pouch</li>
				<li>An explorer's pack and (a) a scholar's pack or (b) any simple weapon</li>
				<li>(a) a scholar's pack or (b) one kit you're proficient in</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE WARMAGE</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Cantrip Bonus Dice</td><td class="col-10">Tricks Known</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 1st</td><td class="left">Spellcasting, Arcane Initiation, Arcane Fighting Style</td><td>4</td><td>0</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 2nd</td><td class="left">Warmage Edge, Warmage Tricks</td><td>4</td><td>0</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 3rd</td><td class="left">Warmage House</td><td>5</td><td>0</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>0</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td class="left">Arcane Surge</td><td>6</td><td>1</td><td>4</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td class="left">Tactical Insight</td><td>6</td><td>1</td><td>4</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td class="left">Warmage House feature</td><td>6</td><td>1</td><td>5</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>1</td><td>5</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>7</td><td>1</td><td>6</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td class="left">Warmage House feature</td><td>7</td><td>1</td><td>6</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td class="left">Arcane Surge Improvement</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>7</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>7</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>8</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td class="left">Strategic Deflection</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>8</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td class="left">Warmage House feature</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>9</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>9</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>10</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td class="left">Warmage House feature</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>10</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>10</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td class="left">Master Warmage</td><td>10</td><td>3</td><td>10</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_SPELLCASTING_WARMAGE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_EDGE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_HOUSE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_WARMAGE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_SURGE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_TACTICAL_INSIGHT" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_STRATEGIC_DEFLECTION" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_MASTER_WARMAGE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description> The undisputed masters of cantrips, warmages turn the most fundamental types of magic into a deadly and precise art.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">The undisputed masters of cantrips, warmages turn the most fundamental types of magic into a deadly and precise art.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_THIRD" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE"/>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Warmage)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE"/>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Warmage)" supports="Artisan tools" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE"/>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Warmage)" supports="Gaming Set" requirements="!ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_SPELLCASTING_WARMAGE" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="1" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_EDGE" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS" level="2" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_HOUSE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_WARMAGE" level="4" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_SURGE" level="5" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_TACTICAL_INSIGHT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_STRATEGIC_DEFLECTION" level="14" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_MASTER_WARMAGE" level="20" />
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_MHP_VSOS_MULTICLASS_WARMAGE">
			<prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">—</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_SPELLCASTING_WARMAGE">
		<description>
			<p>At 1st level, you begin to learn the simple, yet potent, brand of spellcasting for which warmages are known.</p>
			<h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
			<p>You learn four cantrips of your choice from the warmage spell list. You learn additional warmage cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Warmage table. Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warmage cantrips you know and replace it with another warmage cantrip.</p>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
			<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your warmage spells, since you learn your spells through practice and mental discipline. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warmage spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
			</center>
			<h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
			<p>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your warmage spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description> You can use an arcane focus to cast spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Warmage" ability="Intelligence" allowReplace="true">
			<list>Warmage</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="4" spellcasting="Warmage" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="3" number="1" spellcasting="Warmage" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="5" number="1" spellcasting="Warmage" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="9" number="1" spellcasting="Warmage" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="13" number="1" spellcasting="Warmage" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="17" number="1" spellcasting="Warmage" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warmage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="20" number="1" spellcasting="Warmage" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Initiation" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION">
		<description>
			<p>Warmages come from all backgrounds and walks of life. At 1st level, choose where you first learned the basics of magic. The cantrips offered by your initiation don't count against your total number of warmage cantrips known.</p>
			<p><strong>ADVENTURER.</strong> You picked up your magic informally by travelling with a dozen different mages over the years. You learn the <i>mage hand</i> and <i>ray of frost</i> cantrips.</p>
			<p><strong>CIRCUS PERFORMER.</strong> You learned a few simple tricks to participate in a sideshow or circus act. You learn the <i>dancing lights</i> and <i>minor illusion</i> cantrips.</p>
			<p><strong>ELDRITCH EVENT.</strong> An influx of insidious magic left an imprint on you. You learn the <i>chill touch</i> and <i>message</i> cantrips.</p>
			<p><strong>MERCENARY.</strong> You mastered the fundamentals of war magic to engage in battle with similarly-armed arcanists. You learn the <i>arc blade</i> and <i>true strike</i> cantrips.</p>
			<p><strong>TEMPLE.</strong> A monastery or temple educated you in the ways of gentle healing magic. You learn the <i>sacred flame</i> and <i>spare the dying</i> cantrips.</p>
			<p><strong>TOWER APPRENTICE.</strong> You apprenticed under a spellcaster for some time, who taught you the fundamentals of arcana. You learn the <i>prestidigitation</i> and <i>shocking grasp</i> cantrips.</p>
			<p><strong>SELF-TAUGHT.</strong> You taught yourself all the fundamentals of magic from a dusty old tome or abandoned scroll. You learn the <i>fire bolt</i> and <i>light cantrips</i>.</p>
			<p><strong>SURVIVAL.</strong> To survive in the wilderness, you taught yourself to cast simple spells. You learn the <i>druidcraft</i> and <i>shillelagh</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> Choose where you first learned the basics of magic. The cantrips offered by your initiation don't count against your total number of warmage cantrips known.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Arcane Initiation" supports="Arcane Initiation, Warmage" level="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE">
		<description>
			<p>Warmages learn that magic is the purest of weapons, and can be wielded just as easily as any other. At 1st level, select one of the following fighting styles:</p>
			<h5 class="caption">BLASTER</h5>
			<p>The spell save DC for your warmage cantrips increases by 1.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">DEFLECTOR</h5>
			<p>When you have one hand free and a creature hits you with a spell attack or a ranged weapon attack, you can use your reaction to add your proficiency bonus to your Armor Class, potentially causing the attack to miss.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">RESISTIVE</h5>
			<p>While you are wearing light armor or are under the effects of the <i>mage armor</i> spell, you gain a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">SNIPER</h5>
			<p>When making a ranged spell attack, you gain a +1 bonus to the attack roll. Additionally, your ranged cantrips ignore half cover.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">STRIKER</h5>
			<p>When you hit with a cantrip requiring a melee attack and exceed the target's AC by 5 or more or score a critical hit, you can add your proficiency modifier to the damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Arcane Fighting Style" supports="Arcane Fighting Style, Warmage" level="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Warmage Edge" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_EDGE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 2nd level, once on each of your turns when you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can improve one damage roll of the spell, adding your Intelligence modifier to the roll. Starting at 5th level, and as you gain levels in this class, you also add additional dice of cantrip damage, as shown on the Cantrip Bonus Dice column of the Warmage table, to the damage roll. For example, when you are at 5th level, you can enhance the damage of the fire bolt cantrip to deal fire damage equal to 3d10 + your Intelligence modifier on a hit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description level="2">When you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can add your Int modifier to the roll.</description>
			<description level="5">When you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can add your Int modifier to the roll, and 1 additional cantrip damage die.</description>
			<description level="11">When you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can add your Int modifier to the roll, and 2 additional cantrip damage dice.</description>
			<description level="17">When you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can add your Int modifier to the roll, and 3 additional cantrip damage dice.</description>
		</sheet>	
	</element>
	<element name="Warmage Tricks" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 2nd level, you learn a Warmage Trick, a special technique that alters the way you fight, move, and cast your spells. You learn 2 tricks at 2nd level, and an additional trick as shown on the Tricks Known column of the Warmage table.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can replace a trick that you know with another trick for which you meet the prerequisites.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description> You learn 2 tricks at 2nd level, and an additional trick as shown on the Tricks Known column of the Warmage table. Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can replace a trick that you know with another trick for which you meet the prerequisites.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" number="2" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="3" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="5" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="7" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="9" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="11" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="13" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="15" number="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Warmage Trick" supports="Warmage Trick" level="17" number="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Warmage House" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_HOUSE">
		<description>
			<p>The College of Warmages divides its students into distinct Houses, teaching different skills, abilities, and techniques. Upon reaching 3rd level, you can select a House, which offers you features at 3rd level, and additional features at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Warmage House" supports="Warmage House" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_WARMAGE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. You can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warmage 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Warmage,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warmage 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Warmage,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warmage 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Warmage,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warmage 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Warmage,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warmage 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Warmage,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Surge" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_SURGE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 5th level, you learn to, for a moment, tap into a vast reservoir of magical power and unleash it upon your foes. On your turn, when you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can deal twice the number of damage dice dealt by the spell. You can't use this ability on a spell that has scored a critical hit.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. Starting at 11th level, you can use this ability twice between rests.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
			<description> When you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can deal twice the number of damage dice dealt by the spell. Can't use this ability on a spell's critical hit.</description>
			<description level="11" usage="2/Short||Long Rest"> When you deal damage with a warmage cantrip, you can deal twice the number of damage dice dealt by the spell. Can't use this ability on a spell's critical hit.</description>
		</sheet>	
	</element>
	<element name="Tactical Insight" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_TACTICAL_INSIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>At 6th level, you learn how to use ambient magical power to defend yourself from your foes' magical attacks. You can add your Intelligence modifier to saving throws you make against spells and magical effects that deal damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can add your Intelligence modifier to saving throws you make against spells and magical effects that deal damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Strategic Deflection" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_STRATEGIC_DEFLECTION">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level, as a reaction when a creature casts a spell that targets you or includes you in its area of effect and forces you to make a saving throw to avoid damage, you can use your reaction to attempt to redirect some of the spell's energy to a new target. If you succeed on your saving throw against the spell, choose another creature you can see within the spell's range or 30 feet, whichever is closer, to make a saving throw against the spell, using your spell save DC. The new target can be the original spellcaster. On a failed save, the creature suffers the effects of the spell as if you had cast the spell and they had been the original target or been within the area of the spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
			<description> When a creature casts a spell that targets you or includes you in its area of effect and forces you to make a saving throw to avoid damage, and you succeed on it, choose another creature you can see within the spell's range or 30 feet, whichever is closer, to make a saving throw against it, using your spell save DC. The new target can be the original spellcaster. On a failed save, the creature suffers the effects of the spell as if you had cast it and they had been the original target or been within the area of effect.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Master Warmage" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_MASTER_WARMAGE">
		<description>
			<p>At 20th level, you reach the pinnacle of your warmage prowess. If you cast a cantrip which deals 4 dice of damage to a target, it instead deals 5 dice of damage. If you cast a cantrip which makes 4 attacks, it instead makes 5 attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description> If you cast a cantrip which deals 4 dice of damage to a target, it instead deals 5 dice of damage. If you cast a cantrip which makes 4 attacks, it instead makes 5 attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- Arcane Initiation -->
	<element name="Adventurer" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_ADVENTURER">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You picked up your magic informally by travelling with a dozen different mages over the years. You learn the <i>mage hand</i> and <i>ray of frost</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Circus Performer" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_CIRCUS_PERFORMER">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You learned a few simple tricks to participate in a sideshow or circus act. You learn the <i>dancing lights</i> and <i>minor illusion</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Eldritch Event" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_ELDRITCH_EVENT">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An influx of insidious magic left an imprint on you. You learn the <i>chill touch</i> and <i>message</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mercenary" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_MERCENARY">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You mastered the fundamentals of war magic to engage in battle with similarly-armed arcanists. You learn the <i>arc blade</i> and <i>true strike</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_ARC_BLADE" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Temple" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_TEMPLE">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A monastery or temple educated you in the ways of gentle healing magic. You learn the <i>sacred flame</i> and <i>spare the dying</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tower Apprentice" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_TOWER_APPRENTICE">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You apprenticed under a spellcaster for some time, who taught you the fundamentals of arcana. You learn the <i>prestidigitation</i> and <i>shocking grasp</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Self Taught" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_SELF_TAUGHT">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You taught yourself all the fundamentals of magic from a dusty old tome or abandoned scroll. You learn the <i>fire bolt</i> and <i>light cantrips</i>.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Survival" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_INITIATION_SURVIVAL">
		<supports>Arcane Initiation, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>To survive in the wilderness, you taught yourself to cast simple spells. You learn the <i>druidcraft</i> and <i>shillelagh</i> cantrips.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHILLELAGH" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Arcane Fighting Styles -->
	<element name="Blaster" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE_ARCHERY">
		<supports>Arcane Fighting Style, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The spell save DC for your warmage cantrips increases by 1.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The spell save DC for your warmage cantrips increases by 1.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Deflector" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DEFLECTOR">
		<supports>Arcane Fighting Style, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you have one hand free and a creature hits you with a spell attack or a ranged weapon attack, you can use your reaction to add your proficiency bonus to your Armor Class, potentially causing the attack to miss.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Reaction">
			<description> While having one hand free and a creature hits you with a spell or a ranged weapon attack, you can use your reaction to add your PB to your AC, potentially causing the attack to miss.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<!-- <stat name="ac:misc" value="proficiency" bonus="fighting style" equipped="[primary:any],[secondary:none]" alt="Deflector (Arcane Fighting Style)" /> -->
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Resistive" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE_RESISTIVE">
		<supports>Arcane Fighting Style, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you are wearing light armor or are under the effects of the <i>mage armor</i> spell, you gain a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are wearing light armor or are under the effects of the <i>mage armor</i> spell, you gain a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" bonus="fighting style" equipped="[armor:light]" alt="Resistive (Arcane Fighting Style)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sniper" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SNIPER">
		<supports>Arcane Fighting Style, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When making a ranged spell attack, you gain a +1 bonus to the attack roll. Additionally, your ranged cantrips ignore half cover.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When making a ranged spell attack, you gain a +1 bonus to the attack roll. Additionally, your ranged cantrips ignore half cover.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Striker" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_ARCANE_FIGHTING_STYLE_STRIKER">
		<supports>Arcane Fighting Style, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit with a cantrip requiring a melee attack and exceed the target's AC by 5 or more or score a critical hit, you can add your proficiency modifier to the damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!-- Tricks -->
	<element name="Bishop's Manouver" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_BISHOPS_MANOUVER">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Bishops</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_BISHOPS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Bishops</em></p>
			<p>You can take the Disengage action as a bonus action, and when you do so, your movement speed increases by 10 feet until the end of your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can take the Disengage action as a bonus action, and when you do so, your movement speed increases by 10 feet until the end of your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Blasting Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_BLASTING_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Once on each of your turns, when you deal force damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description>When you deal force damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Blinding Light" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_BLINDING_LIGHT">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Light cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Light cantrip</em></p>
			<p>When you use the <i>light</i> cantrip to target an object you are holding, you can direct a flare at a creature within 10 feet of you, which must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature is blinded until the beginning of your next turn. After a creature has failed a saving throw against this ability, it has advantage on all Constitution saving throws against it for 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you use the light cantrip to target an object you are holding, you can direct a flare at a creature within 10 feet of you, which must make a DC{{spellcasting:dc}} CON saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is blinded until the beginning of your next turn. After a creature has failed a saving throw against this ability, it has advantage on all CON saving throws against it for 24 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Castle" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_CASTLE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Rooks</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_ROOKS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Rooks</em></p>
			<p>As an action, you can choose a willing Small or Medium creature you can see within 100 feet of you. You both teleport, switching places.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this trick, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
			<description> You can choose a willing Small or Medium creature you can see within 100 feet of you. You both teleport, switching places.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Chivalrous Presence" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_CHIVALROUS_PRESENCE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>House of Knights</prerequisite>
		<requirements>(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_KNIGHTS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: House of Knights</em></p>
			<p>You gain proficiency in the Insight and Persuasion skills. Additionally, you have advantage on ability checks you make to interact with nobility, and other creatures can always discern when you're telling the truth.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You gain proficiency in the Insight and Persuasion skills, and you have advantage on ability checks you make to interact with nobility, and other creatures can always discern when you're telling the truth.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Cloak of Feathers" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_CLOAK_FEATHERS">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>House of Rooks</prerequisite>
		<requirements>(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_ROOKS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: House of Rooks</em></p>
			<p>While not wearing armor, being under the effects of mage armor, or using a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While not wearing armor, being under the effects of mage armor, or using a shield, your AC equals {{ac:unarmored}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:unarmored:base" value="10" alt="Base" />
            		<stat name="ac:unarmored:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" alt="Dexterity Modifier" />
            		<stat name="ac:unarmored:intelligence" value="intelligence:modifier" alt="Intelligence Modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored" value="ac:unarmored:base" alt="Initial" />
           		<stat name="ac:unarmored" value="ac:unarmored:dexterity" alt="Dexterity Modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored" value="ac:unarmored:intelligence" alt="Intelligence Modifier" />
            		<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none][shield:none]" alt="Unarmored (Cloak of Feathers)" merge="true" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Commander's Steed" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_COMMANDERS_STEED">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>House of Kings</prerequisite>
		<requirements>(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_KINGS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: House of Kings</em></p>
			<p>You learn the <i>find steed</i> spell and can cast it without using a spell slot. Your steed is more resilient than most, and has a number of additional hit points equal to your warmage level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You learn the find steed spell and can cast it without using a spell slot. Your steed is more resilient than most, and has a number of additional hit points equal to your warmage level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_STEED"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Corrosive Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_CORROSIVE_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Once on each of your turns, when you deal acid damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, you can cause the acid to erode the target's defenses. The next time a creature makes an attack roll against the target before the beginning of your next turn, roll a d4 and subtract it from the target's Armor Class for this attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> When you deal acid damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, roll a d4 and subtract it from the target's AC. This lasts until the next time a creature makes an attack roll against the target before the beginning of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Directed Momentum" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_DIRECTED_MOMENTUM">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Lancers</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_LANCERS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Lancers</em></p>
			<p>Once on each of your turns, when you score a critical hit with a melee attack or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make an unarmed strike against a second target. If the target is within range of your Shock Trooper feature, you can lunge toward it. On a hit, this attack deals an additional 1d8 force damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> When you score a critical hit with a melee attack or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make an unarmed strike against a second target. If the target is within range of your Shock Trooper feature, you can lunge toward it. On a hit, this attack deals an additional 1d8 force damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Draining Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_DRAINING_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you deal necrotic or poison damage to a hostile creature using a warmage cantrip, you can siphon some of its life force. You gain temporary hit points equal to half your warmage level, which last for 1 minute.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> Whenever you deal necrotic or poison damage to a hostile creature using a warmage cantrip, you gain temporary hit points equal to half your warmage level, which last for 1 minute.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Encryptogram" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_ENCRYPTOGRAM">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Criptogram cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_CRYPTOGRAM</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Criptogram cantrip</em></p>
			<p>Your knowledge of ciphers has improved your magically clandestine communications. When you cast the <i>cryptogram</i> cantrip, its limit is 20 characters, instead of 8, and only the specified recipient can read the message.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast the cryptogram cantrip, its limit is 20 characters, instead of 8, and only the specified recipient can read the message.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Explosive Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_EXPLOSIVE_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Once on each of your turns, when you deal fire damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, each creature within 5 feet of the target, except yourself and the target, must succeed a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take half the fire damage dealt.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> When you deal fire damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, each creature within 5 feet of the target, except yourself and the target, must succeed a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take half the fire damage dealt.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Extended Range" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_EXTENDED_RANGE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The range of your warmage cantrips is doubled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> The range of your warmage cantrips is doubled.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Field Medic" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_FIELD_MEDIC">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>House of Bishops</prerequisite>
		<requirements>(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_BISHOPS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: House of Bishops</em></p>
			<p>You learn the cantrip <i>spare the dying</i>, which does not count against your maximum number of cantrips known. Additionally, when you cast spare the dying on a creature which has 0 hit points, the target regains 1 hit point and gains temporary hit points equal to your level, which last for 1 minute. Once a creature regains hit points due to this ability, it can't do so again until it finishes a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast spare the dying on a creature which has 0 hit points, the target regains 1 hit point and gains {{level}} temporary hit points, which last for 1 minute. Once a creature regains hit points due to this ability, it can't do so again until it finishes a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Flexible Range" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_FLEXIBLE_RANGE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged spell attack rolls. Additionally, the range of any cantrip you cast that requires a melee spell attack increases to 10 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged spell attack rolls. The range of any cantrip you cast that requires a melee spell attack increases to 10 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Fold" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_FOLD">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Cards</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_CARDS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Cards</em></p>
			<p>You have learned to graciously accept defeat using your Deck of Fate. As a reaction when you are hit by an attack, you can play your entire hand to cast the <i>shield</i> spell without using a spell slot.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short||Long Rest" >
			<description> When you are hit by an attack, you can play your entire hand to cast the shield spell without using a spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Gamble" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_GAMBLE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Cheat cantrip, House of Cards or House of Dice</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_CHEAT,(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_CARDS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_DICE)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Cheat cantrip, House of Cards or House of Dice</em></p>
			<p>You are always under the effects of the <i>cheat</i> cantrip</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you can reroll an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw. Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short||Long Rest" >
			<description> Cheat cantrip permanent effect. Additionally, you can reroll an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Infinite Variation" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_INFINITE_VARIATION">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Prestidigitation cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Prestidigitation cantrip</em></p>
			<p>You have become exceptionally skilled at using the <i>prestidigitation</i> cantrip to mimic other spells. When you cast prestidigitation, you can use it to emulate the effects of any other cantrip that does not deal damage, even one that is not on the warmage spell list. To do so, you must succeed on a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) check, otherwise the spell fizzles and does nothing. A cantrip cast using this trick counts as a warmage cantrip and uses your Intelligence modifier as the spellcasting modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast prestidigitation, you can use it to emulate the effects of any other cantrip that does not deal damage, even one that is not on the warmage spell list. To do so, you must succeed on a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) check, otherwise the spell fails. A cantrip cast using this trick counts as a warmage cantrip and uses your Intelligence modifier as the spellcasting modifier.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Icy Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_ICY_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Once on each of your turns, when you deal cold damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, you can numb the target with a frigid blast. The first time the target makes an attack roll before the end of its next turn, it must roll a d4 and subtract it from the roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> When you deal cold damage to a creature with a warmage cantrip, the first time the target makes an attack roll before the end of its next turn, it must roll a d4 and subtract it from the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Knight's Aegis" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_KNIGHTS_AEGIS">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Knights, Force Buckler cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_KNIGHTS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION),ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_FORCE_BUCKLER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Knights, Force Buckler cantrip</em></p>
			<p>When you cast the <i>force buckler</i> cantrip, you can concentrate on it for up to 1 minute. The spell does not end early if you are hit by an attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast the force buckler cantrip, you can concentrate on it for up to 1 minute. The spell does not end early if you are hit by an attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Leading Edge Tactics" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_LEADING_EDGE_TACTICS">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>House of Lancers</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_LANCERS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: House of Lancers</em></p>
			<p>You always have a plan when engaging the enemy. As such, attacks during the first round of combat have disadvantage against you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> Attacks during the first round of combat have disadvantage against you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Liutenant's Demand" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_LIUTENANTS_DEMAND">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Kings</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],(ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_KINGS||ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_PAWNS_PROMOTION)</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Kings</em></p>
			<p>You can cast the spell <i>command</i> at will without using a spell slot.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can cast the spell command at will without using a spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mage Hand Knack" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Mage Hand cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Mage Hand cantrip</em></p>
			<p>Your skill with the mage hand cantrip allows you to use it as an extension of yourself. When you cast the spell and as a bonus action on each of your subsequent turns, you can use one of the following effects with the hand:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>PRESS.</strong> The hand pushes against a Large or smaller creature within 5 feet of it. Choose a direction away from that creature. Every foot of movement in that direction while the hand is pressing against it costs the creature two feet of movement. The hand continues to push the target until the spell ends or you use your bonus action to use a different effect using the hand.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>PUNCH.</strong> The hand strikes one creature or object within 5 feet of it. Make a melee spell attack for the hand using your spell attack bonus. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 force damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>SEIZE.</strong>The hand grabs a creature of Tiny size and attempts to grapple it. The creature must succeed on a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against your spell save DC or be grappled by the hand. The hand continues to grapple the target until the target uses an action to escape on its turn, the spell ends, or you use your bonus action to use a different effect using the hand.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> Attacks during the first round of combat have disadvantage against you.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK_PRESS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK_PUNCH" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK_SEIZE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Press" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK_PRESS">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The hand pushes against a Large or smaller creature within 5 feet of it. Choose a direction away from that creature. Every foot of movement in that direction while the hand is pressing against it costs the creature two feet of movement. The hand continues to push the target until the spell ends or you use your bonus action to use a different effect using the hand.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description> The hand pushes a Large or smaller creature within 5 feet of it in a direction of your choice. Every foot of movement in that direction costs the creature two feet of movement. This continues until the spell ends or you use your bonus action to use a different effect using the hand.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Punch" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK_PUNCH">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The hand strikes one creature or object within 5 feet of it. Make a melee spell attack for the hand using your spell attack bonus. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 force damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>The hand strikes one creature or object within 5 feet of it. Make a melee spell attack for the hand using your spell attack bonus. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 force damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Seize" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MHK_SEIZE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>The hand grabs a creature of Tiny size and attempts to grapple it. The creature must succeed on a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against your spell save DC or be grappled by the hand. The hand continues to grapple the target until the target uses an action to escape on its turn, the spell ends, or you use your bonus action to use a different effect using the hand.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>The hand grabs a creature of Tiny size and attempts to grapple it. The creature must succeed on a DC{{spellcasting:dc}} Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check or be grappled by the hand. The hand continues to grapple the target until the target uses an action to escape on its turn, the spell ends, or you use your bonus action to use a different effect using the hand.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Minor Shadow Illusion" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MINOR_SHADOW_ILLUSION">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Minor Illusion cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Minor Illusion cantrip</em></p>
			<p>When you create the image of an object in an unoccupied space using the <i>minor illusion</i> cantrip, you can fill it with fibers of shadowstuff, causing it to become partially real. No matter what form the semi-real object takes, it still must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. It has AC 10 and 5 HP, and it weighs 5 pounds. You can only have one semi-real illusion at a time. While this semi-real object exists, the cantrip requires your concentration.</p>
			<p class="indent">The illusion can't replicate a creature, but it can deal damage to a creature within its 5-foot cube. If the illusion is of an object that can deal damage, a creature that enters the object's 5-foot cube or begins its turn there must make an Intelligence saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d6 damage of a type appropriate to the illusion. This damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6). This damage can't trigger Warmage Edge or any warmage tricks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You create an object in an unoccupied space using the minor illusion cantrip, it must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. It has AC 10 and 5 HP, and it weighs 5 pounds. You can only have one at a time. While this object exists, the cantrip requires your concentration. If the illusion is of an object that can deal damage, a creature that enters its space or begins its turn there must make a DC{{spellcasting:dc:int}} INT saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes {{illusiondmg:dice}}d6 damage of a type appropriate to the illusion. This damage can't trigger Warmage Edge or any warmage tricks.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
        	<stat name="illusiondmg:dice" value="1" bonus="illusiondmg" level="2" />
		    <stat name="illusiondmg:dice" value="2" bonus="illusiondmg" level="5" />
		    <stat name="illusiondmg:dice" value="3" bonus="illusiondmg" level="11" />
		    <stat name="illusiondmg:dice" value="4" bonus="illusiondmg" level="17" />
      </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mystical Armor" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MYSTICAL_ARMOR">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can cast the spell <i>mage armor</i> on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can cast the spell mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mystical Athlete" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MYSTICAL_ATHLETE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Quickstep cantrip or Springheel cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_QUICKSTEP||ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_SPRINGHEEL</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Quickstep cantrip or Springheel cantrip</em></p>
			<p>When you cast the <i>quickstep</i> cantrip, your speed increases by 20 feet instead of 10 feet. When you cast the <i>springheel</i> cantrip, your jumping distance increases by 20 feet instead of 10 feet. If you know both of these cantrips, you can cast both of them as part of the same bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast the quickstep cantrip, your speed increases by 20 feet instead of 10 feet. When you cast the springheel cantrip, your jumping distance increases by 20 feet instead of 10 feet. If you know both of these cantrips, you can cast both of them as part of the same bonus action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mystical Weaponmaster" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MYSTICAL_WEAPONMASTER">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Force Weapon cantrip or Magic Daggers cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_FORCE_WEAPON||ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_MAGIC_DAGGERS</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Force Weapon cantrip or Magic Daggers cantrip</em></p>
			<p>Once on each of your turns when you roll a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll for the <i>force weapon</i> or <i>magic daggers</i> cantrips, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> Once on each of your turns when you roll a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll for the force weapon or magic daggers cantrips, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mystical Vision" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_MYSTICAL_VISION">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can cast the spell <i>detect magic</i> at will without expending a spell slot.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can cast the spell detect magic at will without expending a spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Phantom Hookshot" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_PHANTOM_HOOKSHOT">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Phantom Grapnel cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_PHANTOM_GRAPNEL</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Phantom Grapnel cantrip</em></p>
			<p>You can cast the <i>phantom grapnel</i> cantrip as a bonus action. If you do so, its range is reduced to 15 feet. Additionally, creatures pulled by phantom grapnel are pulled an additional 10 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can cast the phantom grapnel as a bonus action. Its range is then reduced to 15 feet. Creatures pulled by phantom grapnel are pulled an additional 10 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Rapid Fortification" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_RAPID_FORTIFICATION">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>Mending cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: Mending cantrip</em></p>
			<p>You can cast the mending cantrip as a bonus action, or you can cast it as an action for one of the following effects:</p>
			<ul>
			 	<li>You can restore a single object, such as a door, cart, wall, or window to pristine condition, if at least half of its parts are present. This object can be no larger than 10 cubic feet, or 1 cubic foot if it is an exceptionally complex object (such as a clock).</li>
			 	<li>You can create simple fortifications, such as sealing a door shut, adding wooden planks to a window, or building a short stone wall (no larger than 10 cubic feet). You must have the materials present to use this ability.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You can cast the mending cantrip as a bonus action, or you can cast it as an action for one of the following effects:
			-You can restore a single object to pristine condition, if at least half of its parts are present. Max size of 10 cubic feet, or 1 cubic foot if it's a really complex one.
			-You can create simple fortifications no larger than 10 cubic feet. You must have the materials present to use this ability.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Snake Eyes" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_SNAKE_EYES">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, House of Dice</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_DICE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, House of Dice</em></p>
			<p>If you roll a 1 or 2 on a Die of Fate, you keep the die instead of giving it to the GM.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> If you roll a 1 or 2 on a Die of Fate, you keep the die instead of giving it to the GM.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Severe Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_SEVERE_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When a creature rolls a 1 on a saving throw against one of your warmage cantrips, it automatically fails the save and takes twice the number of damage dice dealt by the spell, as if you scored a critical hit. The additional damage only applies to the creature that rolled a 1.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When a creature rolls a 1 on one of your warmage cantrips' saving throws, it automatically fails it and takes twice the number of damage dice dealt by the spell. This applies only to the creature that rolled a 1.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Signature Focus" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_SIGNATURE_FOCUS">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 5th level</em></p>
			<p>When you finish a long rest, you can place a unique sigil on a simple weapon, which becomes your signature focus until you use this ability again. This weapon becomes magical, and can be used as an arcane focus. Your signature focus is bonded to you, and gains a number of special abilities:</p>
			<ul>
			 	<li>As a bonus action, you can call your signature focus to your hand, as long as you are on the same plane as it.</li>
			 	<li>You can add your Intelligence modifier, instead of your Strength or Dexterity modifier, to attack rolls using your signature focus.</li>
				<li>Your signature focus gains a number of charges equal to your Intelligence modifier. When you damage a creature with it or a cantrip cast through it, you can expend one charge to deal an additional 1d8 force damage to that creature. Your focus regains all spent charges after you finish a long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you finish a long rest, you can place a unique sigil on a simple weapon, which becomes your signature focus until you use this ability again. It becomes magical, is bonded to you and can be used as an arcane focus. As a bonus action, you can call your signature focus to your hand, as long as you are on the same plane as it. You can add your Int mod, instead of your Str or Dex mod, to attack rolls using your signature focus. It gains {{intelligence:modifier}}charges and when you damage a creature with it or a cantrip cast through it, you can expend one charge to deal an additional 1d8 force damage to that creature. It regains all spent charges after a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Silent Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_SILENT_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Once on each of your turns when you deal thunder damage to a hostile creature with a warmage cantrip, you can create a 15-foot diameter sphere of magical silence, centered on yourself or the creature (your choice), which lasts until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> When you deal thunder damage to a hostile creature with a warmage cantrip, you can create a 15-foot diameter sphere of magical silence, centered on yourself or the creature (your choice), which lasts until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Split Fire" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_SPLIT_FIRE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 5th level</em></p>
			<p>When you cast a warmage cantrip that requires a single spell attack roll, you can select multiple creatures and make a spell attack roll against each. You can target a number of creatures equal to the number of damage dice the cantrip deals, and split your damage dice up amongst your targets, to a minimum of 1 die of damage per target. Each attack must target a different creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">For example, fire bolt deals 3d10 damage. You can choose to target three creatures and deal 1d10 damage to each creature, or you can target two creatures, dealing 1d10 damage to one creature and 2d10 damage to the other creature, or you can target one creature for 3d10 damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast a warmage cantrip that requires a single spell attack roll, you can target a number of creatures up to the number of damage dice the cantrip deals, make a spell attack roll against each, and split your damage dice up amongst your targets, to a minimum of 1 die of damage per target. Each attack must target a different creature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Static Cantrip" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_STATIC_CANTRIP">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you deal lightning damage to a hostile creature using a warmage cantrip, you can sap part of the energy into a charge which clings to your body until the beginning of your next turn. While charged, you can use your reaction when you take damage from a creature you can see within 5 feet of you to deal lightning damage equal to half your warmage level to the creature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description> Whenever you deal lightning damage using a warmage cantrip, you gain a charge which clings to your body until the start of your next turn. You can then use your reaction when you take damage from a creature you can see within 5 feet of you to deal {{level:warmage:half}}lightning damage to that creature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unerring Strike" type="Class Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_CLASS_FEATURE_WARMAGE_WMG_TRICKS_UNERRING_STRIKE">
		<supports>Warmage Trick, Warmage</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th level, True Strike cantrip</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10],ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 10th level, True Strike cantrip</em></p>
			<p>When you cast the <i>true strike</i> cantrip, you can concentrate on it for a number of rounds equal to your Intelligence modifier. You gain advantage on the first attack roll you make against the target each round while maintaining concentration on true strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you cast the true strike cantrip, you can concentrate on it for {{intelligence:modifier}}rounds. You gain advantage on the first attack roll you make against the target each round while maintaining concentration on true strike.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>	
