<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
      <name>Mage Hand Magus</name>
      <description>The Mage Hand Magus from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
      <author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
      <update version="0.0.1">
        <file name="fighter-mage-hand-magus.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/fighter-mage-hand-magus.xml" />
      </update>    
    </info>
    <element name="Mage Hand Magus" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM">
      <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
      <description>
        <p>Blades sweeping around in dramatic arcs, propelled by ghostly, disembodied hands—the Mage Hand Magi are truly a force to be reckoned with. While wizards are content to use mage hand to retrieve their wands and open doors from across the room, the cantrip’s potential has always been clear for warriors: a deft mage hand can afford dozens of feet between a soldier and their foe, letting them deal a killing blow without raising a fingertip. Mage Hand Magi have mastered this cantrip through practice and discipline, elaborating a trick pioneered by warmages into a deadly fighting style of twin hovering blades. The most skilled can even manifest a warhand, a grand fist of magical wrath, with which to crush their enemies.</p>
        <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_MAGE_HAND_MASTER" />
        <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_COMBAT_HANDS" />
        <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HANDY_MANEUVERS" />
        <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_WARHAND" />
        <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HANDGLIDE" />
        <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HEAVY_HANDED" />
      </description>
      <sheet display="false" />
      <rules>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_MAGE_HAND_MASTER" level="3" />
        <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_COMBAT_HANDS" level="3" />
        <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HANDY_MANEUVERS" level="7" />
        <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_WARHAND" level="10" />
        <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HANDGLIDE" level="15" />
        <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HEAVY_HANDED" level="18" />
      </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mage Hand Master" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_MAGE_HAND_MASTER">
      <description>
        <p>Starting at 3rd level, when you choose this archetype, you learn the mage hand cantrip if you did not know it before. You can cast it with the following improvements:</p>
        <ul class="unstyled">
          <li> You can cast and control mage hand as a bonus action.</li>
          <li> You summon two separate hands when you cast it, and you can control one or both of them when you use the spell.</li>
          <li> The spell's duration is indefinite, ending only when you are knocked unconscious or you choose to end it.</li>
          <li> Your mage hands are stronger than normal, capable of lifting a combined weight in pounds equal to 5 x your fighter level, and they are dexterous enough to perform any ability check you could normally perform with your hands.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description> You learn the mage hand cantrip if you did not know it before, with the following improvements:
        You can cast and control mage hand as a bonus action.
        You summon two separate hands, and you can control one or both of them when you use the spell.
        The spell's duration is indefinite, ending only when you are knocked unconscious or you choose to end it.
        Your mage hands are capable of lifting a combined weight equal to 5x{{fighter:level}}lbs, and they are dexterous enough to perform any ability check you could normally perform with your hands.</description>
	    </sheet>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" />
      </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Combat Hands" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_COMBAT_HANDS">
      <description>
        <p>At 3rd level, you have learned to use your mage hands in combat. While you are holding nothing in your hands, your mage hands can wield weapons: each can wield a single one-handed weapon, or together they can wield a two-handed weapon.</p>
        <p class="indent">When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one or more of your attacks through your mage hands against targets you can see within their reach. You can add your Intelligence modifier, instead of your Strength or Dexterity, to the attack and damage rolls. A mage hand not wielding a weapon can be used to punch a creature within 5 feet of it, dealing 1d6 force damage on a hit.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description> While you are holding nothing in your hands, your mage hands can wield weapons: each can wield a single one-handed weapon, or together they can wield a two-handed weapon. You can make one or more of your attacks through your mage hands against targets you can see within their reach. You can add your Intelligence modifier, instead of your Strength or Dexterity, to the attack and damage rolls. A mage hand not wielding a weapon deals 1d6 force damage on a hit.</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Handy Maneuvers" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HANDY_MANEUVERS">
      <description>
        <p>Starting at 7th level, you can use your mage hands to perform a number of combat maneuvers or tricks. While they are not wielding weapons, you can use both of your hands together to grapple or shove a creature. When you do so, you add your Intelligence modifier to the Strength (Athletics) check.</p>
        <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use your reaction to make an opportunity attack with one of your hands when a creature leaves its reach.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description> You can use your mage hands to perform a number of combat maneuvers or tricks. While they are not wielding weapons, you can use both of your hands together to grapple or shove a creature. When you do so, you add your Intelligence modifier to the Strength (Athletics) check. You can use your reaction to make an opportunity attack with one of your hands when a creature leaves its reach.</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Warhand" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_WARHAND">
      <description>
        <p>Starting at 10th level, when you cast <em>mage hand</em>, you can form one of them into a much more powerful construct called a warhand. Your warhand is identical to the hand summoned by the spell <em>arcane hand</em>(Bigby's Hand), except that you must use its abilities as an action, instead of a bonus action. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell. When you use any of the warhand’s abilities, you can use a bonus action to make a single attack with your other mage hand.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description> When you cast mage hand, you can form one of them into a much more powerful construct called a warhand. It's identical to the one summoned by the arcane hand spell, except that you must use its abilities as an action, instead of a bonus action. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell. When you use any of the warhand’s abilities, you can use a bonus action to make a single attack with your other mage hand.</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Handglide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HANDGLIDE">
      <description>
        <p>By 15th level, while two summoned mage hands or a warhand are within 5 feet of you, the hands can hold you aloft and carry you to your destination. You can have a flight speed equal to your movement speed while the hands carry you.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description> While two summoned mage hands or a warhand are within 5 feet of you, the hands can hold you aloft and carry you to your destination. You can have a flight speed equal to your movement speed while the hands carry you.</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Heavy Handed" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_MHM_HEAVY_HANDED">
      <description>
        <p>Starting at 18th level, you can summon two warhands instead of mage hands when you cast the mage hand spell. You can use the abilities of both warhands as part of the same action on your turn.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description> You can summon two warhands instead of mage hands when you cast the mage hand spell. You can use the abilities of both warhands as part of the same action on your turn.</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>