<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Beastborne</name>
        <description>The Beastborne from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
        <author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="ranger-beastborne.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/ranger-beastborne.xml" />
        </update>    
    </info>
    <element name="Beastborne" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_RANGER_BEASTBORNE">
        <supports>Ranger Archetype, Ranger Conclave</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Whether by infected bite or insidious curse, your blood was marked by the indelible stain of beasthood, a curse of lycanthropy. A new form, a primal, bestial self lies just beneath your skin, awaiting the allure of blood and the thrill of a hunt to emerge in a terrible spectacle. Perhaps, if you can avoid the violence of combat or the siren call of moonlight, you can resist the lycanthropic urge. Or perhaps you see the infection as a blessing, a fearsome weapon, with claws that rend and teeth that bite.</p>
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_SHAPECHANGER" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_BESTIAL_ASPECT" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_WOLFBANE_FURY" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_HOWLING_CARNAGE" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_RELENTLESS_BLOODLUST" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_SHAPECHANGER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_BESTIAL_ASPECT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_WOLFBANE_FURY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_HOWLING_CARNAGE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_RELENTLESS_BLOODLUST" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shapechanger" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_SHAPECHANGER">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your body is stained by a lycanthropic curse, which struggles to escape from you at all times. You gain the shapechanger subtype; your true form is a ghastly hybrid of beast and man. Additionally, you gain the following abilities:</p>
            <p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>DARKVISION.</strong> You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision from your race, its range increases by 30 feet.</p>
            <p style="text-indent: -1em; margin-left: 1em"><strong>KEEN SMELL.</strong> You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
			<description>You gain the shapechanger subtype. Additionally, you gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have it from your race, its range increases by 30 feet. You also have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" type="Vision"/>
		</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bestial Aspect" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_BESTIAL_ASPECT">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, as blood is shed, you gradually lose control and slip into a beastlike form, ravenous and hungry for carnage. Whenever you take damage or deal damage to a hostile creature with an attack, add the total number together; this is your damage pool. You gain a bonus to your damage rolls, as well as additional beastlike abilities, according to your total damage pool, as shown on the Bestial Aspect table. After 1 minute of taking and dealing no damage, reset your damage pool to 0.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Bestial Aspect</h5>
            <table>
			    <thead>
			    <tr><td>Damage Pool</td><td>Damage Bonus</td><td>Ability</td></tr>
			    </thead>
			    <tr><td>0</td><td>--</td><td>--</td></tr>
			    <tr><td>10</td><td>+2</td><td>You sprout a set of vicious claws, which are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</td></tr>
			    <tr><td>20</td><td>+2</td><td>You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons that aren’t silvered.</td></tr>
			    <tr><td>30</td><td>+2</td><td>Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>40</td><td>+3</td><td>You gain blindsight with a range of 10 feet.</td></tr>
			    <tr><td>50</td><td>+3</td><td>You gain a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.</td></tr>
			    <tr><td>70</td><td>+3</td><td>Your movement speed increases by an additional 10 feet (20 feet total).</td></tr>
			    <tr><td>100</td><td>+3</td><td>Your claws deal an additional 1d6 slashing damage on a hit.</td></tr>
		    </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> Whenever you take damage or deal damage to a hostile creature with an attack, add the total number together; this is your damage pool. You gain a bonus to your damage rolls, as well as additional beastlike abilities, according to your total damage pool, as shown on the Bestial Aspect table. After 1 minute of taking and dealing no damage, reset your damage pool to 0.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Wolfbane Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_WOLFBANE_FURY">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, you can whip yourself into a lycanthropic fury. As a bonus action, you can roll 4d6 and add the total to your damage pool. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
            <description> You can roll 4d6 and add the total to your damage pool.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Howling Carnage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_HOWLING_CARNAGE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 11th level, whenever your damage pool exceeds 50, you attack three times with your claws, instead of twice, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> Whenever your damage pool exceeds 50, you attack three times with your claws, instead of twice, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Relentless Bloodlust" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_BEAST_RELENTLESS_BLOODLUST">
        <description>
            <p>By 15th level, not even death can hold back your transformation. When you are reduced to 0 hit points and are not killed outright, you can choose to drop to 1 hit point instead. Add the total damage you would have taken to your damage pool. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points and are not killed outright, you can choose to drop to 1 hit point instead. Add the total damage you would have taken to your damage pool.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>