<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>House of Kings</name>
        <description>The Warmage's House of Kings from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
        <author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com/">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="warmage-kings.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/warmage-kings.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="House of Kings" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_HOUSE_KINGS">
        <supports>Warmage House</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Warmages who train in the House of Kings specialize in tactics and strategy, learning age-old maneuvers to give them the edge in combat. Natural-born leaders, Kings work best with a cadre of supporters to perform their tactics and overwhelm the enemy. Moreso than all other warmages, those in the House of Kings treat life and death as little more than a game of strategy to be understood and conquered.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_BATTLE_TACTICS" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_LEAD_FROM_THE_FRONT" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_TACTICAL_MASTER" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_CHECKMATE" />
            <div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_GRANDMASTER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_BATTLE_TACTICS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_LEAD_FROM_THE_FRONT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_TACTICAL_MASTER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_CHECKMATE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_GRANDMASTER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
        <description>
            <p>When you choose this house at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, battleaxes, longswords, tridents, lances, and warhammers.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_BATTLEAXE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_TRIDENT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LANCE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WARHAMMER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Battle Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_BATTLE_TACTICS">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you learn stratagems that are fueled by special dice called Battle dice.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>BATTLE DICE.</strong> You have two battle dice, which are d8s. A battle die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your battle dice when you take a short or long rest, or when you roll initiative.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your battle die changes and more battle dice become available when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown on the table below.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warmage Level</td><td>Battle Dice</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>2d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>3d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>3d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>4d10</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent"><strong>USING BATTLE DICE.</strong>Once per turn, you can expend a battle die to perform a stratagem of your choice. Your stratagem options are detailed at the end of the subclass description.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>SAVING THROWS.</strong>When a stratagem calls for a saving throw to resist its effects, use your spell save DC.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Turn">
	    <description>You learn stratagems that are fueled by special dice called Battle Dice. You have {{battle dice:amount}} Battle dice which are d{{battle dice:size}}s. You regain all dice after a short or long rest, or when you roll initiative. Your stratagems DC is {{spellcasting:dc:int}}.</description>
	</sheet>
	<rules>
	    <stat name="battle dice:amount" value="2" />
	    <stat name="battle dice:amount" value="1" level="7" />
	    <stat name="battle dice:amount" value="1" level="19" />
	    <stat name="battle dice:size" value="8" bonus="size"/>
            <stat name="battle dice:size" value="10" bonus="size" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_BLITZ" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_CHECK" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_FLASH_OF_BRILLIANCE" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_GAMBIT" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_MYSTIC_COUNSEL" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_STALEMATE"  />
	</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lead from the Front" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_LEAD_FROM_THE_FRONT">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, you and each friendly creature within 100 feet that can see you ignores nonmagical difficult terrain.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> You and each friendly creature within 100 feet that can see you ignores nonmagical difficult terrain.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tactical Master" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_TACTICAL_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 10th level, friendly creatures within 10 feet of you add your Intelligence modifier to saving throws against spells and magical effects that deal damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> Friendly creatures within 10 feet of you add {{intelligence:modifier}} to saving throws against spells and magical effects that deal damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Stratagem: Checkmate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_CHECKMATE">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, you learn the following maneuver:</p>
            <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with a weapon or spell attack, you can use your bonus action and expend a battle die to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you that is within reach of the creature you hit. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack or cast a cantrip requiring an attack roll, adding the battle die to the attack's damage roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description> When you hit a creature with a weapon or spell attack, you can expend a battle die to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you that is within reach of the creature you hit. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack or cast a cantrip requiring an attack roll, adding the battle die to the attack's damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Grandmaster" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_GRANDMASTER">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 18th level, when you roll initiative, choose a number of friendly creatures equal to your Intelligence modifier that can hear or see you to gain a battle die. Once within the next 10 minutes, the creatures can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, damage roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it makes the roll before deciding to add the battle die, but must decide before the GM declares the roll's outcome. Once the battle die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one battle die from this feature at a time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> When you roll initiative, choose {{intelligence:modifier}} friendly creatures that can hear or see you to gain a battle die. Once within the next 10 minutes, the creatures can roll the die and add the result to one ability check, attack/damage roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it makes the roll before adding the battle die, but must decide before the GM declares the roll's outcome. Once the battle die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one battle die from this feature at a time.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Stratagems -->
    <element name="Blitz" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_BLITZ">
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, when you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one battle die to maneuver one of your comrades into a more advantageous position. Choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without provoking opportunity attacks from the target of your attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description> When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one battle die to maneuver one of your comrades into a more advantageous position. Choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without provoking opportunity attacks from the target of your attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Check" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_CHECK">
        <description>
            <p>When you hit a creature with an attack, as a bonus action you can spend one battle die to force that creature to flee. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. A creature that is immune to being charmed automatically succeeds this saving throw. On a failed save, the target must immediately use its reaction, if available, to move up to half its speed directly away from you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description> When you hit a creature with an attack, you can spend one battle die to force that creature to flee. The target must make a CHA saving throw. A creature that is immune to being charmed automatically succeeds this saving throw. On a failed save, the target must immediately use its reaction, if available, to move up to half its speed directly away from you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Flash of Brilliance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_FLASH_OF_BRILLIANCE">
        <description>
            <p>When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom ability check, you can expend and roll one battle die to add its result to your ability check. You can choose to use this stratagem after the ability check is rolled but before the GM declares whether the result was a success or failure.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom ability check, you can expend and roll one battle die to add its result to your ability check. You can choose to use this stratagem after the ability check is rolled but before the GM declares whether the result was a success or failure.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Gambit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_GAMBIT">
        <description>
            <p>When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one battle die to give your allies an opening. The next creature other than you to make an attack against the target adds the battle die to their attack roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one battle die to give your allies an opening. The next creature other than you to make an attack against the target adds the battle die to their attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mystic Counsel" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_MYSTIC_COUNSEL">
        <description>
            <p>You can use a bonus action and expend one battle die to give counsel to a creature that can hear you within 30 feet. Once in the next minute when the creature makes a saving throw against a spell it can choose to roll the battle die and add its result to the saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description> You expend one battle die to give counsel to a creature that can hear you within 30 feet. Once in the next minute when the creature makes a saving throw against a spell it can choose to roll the battle die and add its result to the saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Stalemate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HOUSE_KINGS_STRATAGEM_STALEMATE">
        <description>
            <p>When you hit a creature with an attack, as a bonus action you can expend one battle die to hold that creature in place. Until the end of its next turn, the target can't willingly move unless it first takes the Disengage action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description> When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one battle die to hold that creature in place. Until the end of its next turn, the target can't willingly move unless it first takes the Disengage action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>
