<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>School of Chronomancy</name>
		<description>The School of Chronomancy from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
		<author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="wizard-school-chronomancy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/wizard-school-chronomancy.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="School of Chronomancy" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_CHRONOMANCY">
		<supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The School of Chronomancy focuses on harnessing and manipulating the energies of flowing time. It is a perilous tradition, as the practice of slowing, reversing, or diverting the flow of time can accidently tear novices to pieces, spreading them thinly across millennia, or sometimes even drop them wholesale into a new era, with no way of returning home. Masters of this school, however, walk the generations as planeshifters walk the cosmos, literally ending most conflicts before they even begin.</p>
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_CHRONOMANCY_SAVANT" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_CHRONOSHIFT" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_LAG_SPELL" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_FOREIMAGE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
        <setters>
			<set name="short">Practitioners of elusive and catastrophic chronomancy or “time magic”</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_CHRONOMANCY_SAVANT" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_CHRONOSHIFT" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_LAG_SPELL" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_FOREIMAGE" level="14"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Chronomancy Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_CHRONOMANCY_SAVANT">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, all spells with the chronomancy tag are added to the wizard spell list for you. Additionally, the time you must spend to copy a spell into your spellbook equals 10 minutes per spell level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>All spells with the chronomancy tag are added to the wizard spell list for you. Additionally, the time you must spend to copy a spell into your spellbook equals 10 minutes per spell level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Wizard" extend="true">
			<extend>ID_MHP_VSOS_SPELL_INSTANT_REPLAY</extend>
		</spellcasting>
	</element>
	<element name="Chronoshift" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_CHRONOSHIFT">
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, you can abate time while casting your spells. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that has a casting time of 1 action, you can expend another spell slot of the same level to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{chronoshift}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that has a casting time of 1 action, you can expend another spell slot of the same level to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
            <stat name="chronoshift" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="chronoshift" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Speed of Thought" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT">
		<description>
			<p>By 6th level, you can enter a state of heightened focus as an action, allowing you to perform certain tasks five times faster than normal while you concentrate on them like a spell. These tasks must be purely intellectual in nature, such as research, translation, or computation, and must be tasks you can complete alone; others can't understand your speech or meaningfully help while you are working at increased speed. Furthermore, attempting to cast a spell, perform a ritual, or move further than 10 feet from where you began instantly returns you to the normal flow of time with a feeling of faintness which prevents you from maintaining concentration for 1 minute.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can enter a state of heightened focus, allowing you to perform certain tasks five times faster than normal while you concentrate on them like a spell. These tasks must be purely intellectual in nature, such as research, translation, or computation, and must be tasks you can complete alone; others can't understand your speech or meaningfully help while you are working at increased speed. Furthermore, attempting to cast a spell, perform a ritual, or move further than 10 feet from where you began instantly returns you to the normal flow of time with a feeling of faintness which prevents you from maintaining concentration for 1 minute.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Lag Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_LAG_SPELL">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, when you cast a spell, you can delay its effect for one, two, or three turns. When the spell is cast, you choose the spell's target and the number of rounds to delay the spell, and you roll any relevant attack rolls. Any effects on the spell's targets, including saving throws, are resolved when the spell triggers at the start of your turn after the chosen number of rounds. You don't concentrate on a delayed spell that requires concentration until it takes effect. If any conditions change between casting and when the spell takes effect that would make the spell impossible—such as the target leaving the spell's maximum range—the spell fails.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short||Long Rest">
			<description>When you cast a spell, you choose the spell's target and the number of rounds to delay the spell (one, two, or three turns), and you roll any relevant attack rolls. Any effects on the spell's targets, including saving throws, are resolved when the spell triggers at the start of your turn after the chosen number of rounds. You don't concentrate on a delayed spell that requires concentration until it takes effect. If any conditions change between casting and when the spell takes effect that would make the spell impossible, the spell fails.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Foreimage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_CHRONOMANCY_FOREIMAGE">
		<description>
			<p>By 14th level, you have unlocked the power to turn back time and retrace your steps, correcting your most egregious errors. Whenever you finish a long rest, you are actually beginning your second attempt at the day's events. You are accompanied by a temporal shadow, an echo of your first time experiencing the day, which you follow perfectly in order to repeat the day's events. Acting on your foreknowledge destroys your temporal shadow until you finish a long rest, but allows you to use one of the following abilities:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain advantage on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make.</li>
				<li>You can cause one attack roll that doesn't have advantage to miss you.</li>
				<li>You can act on the knowledge of one thing that you could have known before the end of the day, such as the answer to a riddle, the location of a pit trap, the path through a labyrinth, or someone's name.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Once you use this ability, all remaining foreknowledge leaves you until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you are accompanied by a temporal shadow, an echo of your first time experiencing the day, which you follow perfectly in order to repeat the day's events. Acting on your foreknowledge destroys your temporal shadow until you finish a LR, but allows you to use one of the following abilities:&#13;
			• You gain advantage on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make.&#13;
			• You can cause one attack roll that doesn't have advantage to miss you.&#13;
			• You can act on the knowledge of one thing that you could have known before the end of the day.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>