<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>School of Somnomancy</name>
		<description>The School of Somnomancy from Valda's Spire of Secrets</description>
		<author url="https://mfov.magehandpress.com">Valda's Spire of Secrets</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="wizard-school-somnomancy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Valdas-Spire-of-Secrets/main/elements/valdas-spire-of-secrets/wizard-school-somnomancy.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="School of Somnomancy" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_SOMNOMANCY">
		<supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Somnomancers are an idiosyncratic bunch, given to fancies, daydreams, and odd sartorial choices, so it is no surprise that their subschool of magic is rarely accorded any respect by mages of other schools. Although their obsession with sleep is occasionally useful, such as when someone needs to be hypnotized or must have their dreams interpreted, it is more often a source of humor—much to the chagrin of so-called “pajama mages”!</p>
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_SOMNAMBULIST" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_DEEP_SLEEP" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_MESMERIZE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_DREAMSPEAKER" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_FITFUL_SLUMBER" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
        <setters>
			<set name="short">So-called “pajama mages” who master sleep and trance-related magic</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_SOMNAMBULIST" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_DEEP_SLEEP" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_MESMERIZE" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_DREAMSPEAKER" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_FITFUL_SLUMBER" level="14"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Somnambulist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_SOMNAMBULIST">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, your mastery over sleep magic has rendered you a persistent sleep-walker. While you are asleep, you can move around freely; you don't fully perceive your environment while asleep, so you must navigate from memory. Additionally, you can copy spells to your spellbook while asleep.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While you are asleep, you can move around freely; you don't fully perceive your environment while asleep, so you must navigate from memory. Additionally, you can copy spells to your spellbook while asleep.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Deep Sleep" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_DEEP_SLEEP">
		<description>
			<p>Also at 2nd level, you add the <i>sleep</i> spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. Whenever you cast this spell, it is improved in the following ways:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The total number of hit points that can be affected is equal to double the number rolled on the dice.</li>
				<li>The radius of the spell is increased to 30 feet.</li>
				<li>You can freely choose the order in which creatures are affected by a <i>sleep</i> spell you cast.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You add the Sleep spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. Whenever you cast this spell, it is improved in the following ways: hp that can be affected equal to double the number rolled on the dice, spell radius is increased to 30ft, you can freely choose the order in which creatures are affected by the spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mesmerize" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_MESMERIZE">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 6th level, by performing a repetitive action for 1 minute, you can hypnotize a willing or unconscious creature within 60 feet that can see or hear you.</p>
			<p class="indent">While hypnotized by you, it is semi-conscious and charmed by you. Other spells and effects that charm the creature or influence its mind have no effect while the creature is hypnotized. If you choose, you can cause a creature to repeat its saving throw against these effects, ending an effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">The creature has the ability to perfectly recall its memories while hypnotized, including memories that have been magically altered or suppressed. While hypnotized, the creature will truthfully answer any question you pose to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lastly, you can specify a single command word to be embedded in the creature's subconscious for up to 24 hours. The first time the creature hears the command word while it isn't hypnotized, it immediately performs the single action or repeats a certain phrase that you specified while the creature was hypnotized. The creature performs this action or speaks this phrase even if the effects of a spell would compel them to act otherwise.</p>
			<p class="indent">The creature remains hypnotized by you for up to 1 hour, or until it takes damage or you end it early by snapping your fingers.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>By performing a repetitive action for 1 minute, you can hypnotize a willing or unconscious creature within 60ft that can see or hear you.&#13;
			While hypnotized by you, it is semi-conscious and charmed by you. Other spells and effects that charm the creature or influence its mind have no effect while the creature is hypnotized. If you choose, you can cause a creature to repeat its saving throw against these effects, ending an effect on itself on a success.&#13;
			The creature has the ability to perfectly recall its memories while hypnotized, including those that have been magically altered or suppressed. While hypnotized, the creature will truthfully answer any question you pose to it.&#13;
			You can specify a single command word to be embedded in the creature's subconscious for up to 24 hours. The first time the creature hears the command word while it isn't hypnotized, it immediately performs the single action or repeats a certain phrase that you specified while the creature was hypnotized. The creature performs this action or speaks this phrase even if the effects of a spell would compel them to act otherwise.&#13;
			The creature remains hypnotized by you for up to 1 hour, or until it takes damage or you end it early by snapping your fingers.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Dreamspeaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_DREAMSPEAKER">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, you add the spell <i>dream</i> to your spellbook if it is not there already. When you cast this spell, the messenger may jump between up to 12 creatures (each makes their saving throw against the spell separately), conversing with any or all of them. They can only appear monstrous to one of the targets, however, and the spell ends immediately after that option is utilized.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You add the spell Dream to your spellbook if it is not there already. When you cast this spell, the messenger may jump between up to 12 creatures (each makes their saving throw against the spell separately), conversing with any or all of them. They can only appear monstrous to one of the targets, however, and the spell ends immediately after that option is utilized.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Fitful Slumber" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets" id="ID_MHP_VSOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIZARD_SOMNOMANCY_FITFUL_SLUMBER">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 14th level, you can give creatures that you put to sleep terrible nightmares. At the start of their turn, you can choose to make any creature that is under the influence of a <i>sleep</i> spell that you cast take 3d6 psychic damage. This damage can't wake a creature up, nor can it reduce a creature below 1 hit point.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can give creatures that you put to sleep terrible nightmares. At the start of their turn, you can choose to make any creature that is under the influence of a Sleep spell that you cast take 3d6 psychic damage. This damage can't wake a creature up, nor can it reduce a creature below 1hp.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>